Vyacheslav Zavertanny

+1 (111) 111-1111 | dev@zavertanny.com | linkedin.com/in/zavertanny

Summary

Software engineer with 6+ years of designing and building web and mobile applications. Specialized in frontend development using modern frameworks and libraries like React, Vue, and Angular. Have extensive experience in starting apps from scratch as well as supporting and further developing existing projects. Looking for a senior frontend developer role, interested in solving complex technical problems in various domains and evolving as a full-stack engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Frontend Developer

May 2020 - Present

Freedom Finance Investment Company

Moscow, Russia

- Improved trading terminal frontend architecture by combining separated modules into a mono repository for better developer experience and reducing feature delivery time
- Developed applications for internal use such as corporate portal, client support, and back office which are essential to the company's business and help to address customers' and employees' needs
- Built a small team of frontend developers, mentoring, and growing teammates from junior to middle level

Senior Frontend Developer

Nov 2017 - May 2020

Banki.ru (Russian financial marketplace)

Moscow, Russia

- Implemented UI for a new trip abroad section that allows clients to purchase an insurance policy in a few clicks
- Designed insurance salesman dashboard that helps car owners to find offers with lower fees
- Optimized webpack build, reduced frontend bundle size and total building time

Frontend/Mobile Developer

Aug 2016 – Oct 2017

Webox LLC (Khana2Go food ordering and delivery app)

St Louis, MO, USA

- Created the hybrid mobile application using PhoneGap/Cordova that reduced the cost of cross-platform development
- Imitated native mobile apps behaviour (responsiveness, smooth transitions and animations) using Framework7 library for better user experience
- Minimized server load and building/loading time by excluding 3rd party libraries from the resulting bundle and loading via CDN

Side Projects

MedAdvisor Jan 2021 – Present

<u>MedAdvisor</u> is a startup that aggregates healthcare services across Russia and helps patients find clinics based on ratings, reviews and location. My role here is to design a frontend architecture for the whole site and implement the user interface according to design mockups.

 $\mathbf{JOOR.me} \qquad \qquad \mathbf{Feb} \ 2016 - \mathbf{Apr} \ 2018$

Publishing service for online magazines. The main challenge in this project was to implement a user-friendly UI for creating magazine issues, including a Photoshop-like graphic editor (HTML5 Canvas, Fabric.js) for covers and a feature-rich text editor (React, Draft.js) for articles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

 ${\bf Programming\ languages:\ JavaScript,\ TypeScript,\ HTML/CSS}$

Frameworks: React/Redux, React Native, Vue, Angular

Styling: SASS, LESS, Stylus, PostCSS, BEM Testing: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Puppeteer

Developer Tools: Node.js, Webpack, Babel, Eslint, Lerna, Docker

Libraries: Redux Saga, Redux Thunk, Redux Form, Apollo GraphQL, RxJS, Material-UI, jQuery

EDUCATION

Far Eastern Federal University

Vladivostok, Russia